Where there is Six Harmonies, there is peace and joy; where there is the practice of
ở đâu có Lục Hòa ở đó có an vui ở đâu tu
Six Harmonies, there is liberation. Greetings to all of
Lục Hòa ở đó có giải thoát Xin chào quý
you! Surely, the lyrics we just
vị và các bạn chắc hẳn những lời hát vừa
heard are very familiar to the
rồi đã rất quen thuộc đối với các phật
Buddhist practitioners in the Golden Chrysanthemum Club who practice Six Harmonies,
tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập tu Lục
right? And March 0th,
Hòa đúng không ạ Và ngày mùng 0 tháng 3
2024 is also the anniversary
năm 2024 cũng là ngày kỉ niệm sinh nhật
of our Golden Chrysanthemum Club's birthday. I
của câu lạc bộ Quốc vàng chúng ta không
wonder how the Buddhist practitioners feel?
biết cảm xúc của các phật tử như thế nào
As for me, Doan Linh, I feel
ạ Còn đối với Doãn Linh linh cảm thấy
very honored and proud to be
rất là vinh dự và tự hào khi được làm
a small part of the club and to
một phần nhỏ của câu lạc bộ cũng như
witness its development.
chứng kiến sự phát triển của câu lạc bộ
Dear friends, to have a club that
đó ạ quý vị thân mến để có được một câu
practices harmoniously as it does
lạc bộ sinh hoạt tu tập hòa hợp như ngày
today, the members
hôm nay các thành viên trong câu lạc bộ
always remember the blessings of the Three Jewels, express gratitude for the merits of our master and the great Sangha,
luôn nhớ về ân đức của tam bảo tri ân
practice according to the Buddha's teachings, create good karma to reap
thực hành theo lời Phật dạy tạo nhân
good results. Among all good deeds, there is
lành thì hưởng quả tốt trong các nhân
no better than the act of bowing to the
lành không có nhân lành nào Thù Thắng
Buddha and making offerings to the
hơn nhân thở phật lạy phật và cúng dường
Three Jewels. It is for this reason that today, on the anniversary of the
tam bảo chính vì lý do đó Hôm nay hướng
Golden Chrysanthemum Club's birthday, we have made the vow to attain enlightenment.  Offering
Quốc vàng đã phát nguyện Đạt bát cúng
alms to the Venerable Monks, some Buddhists
dường Chư Tôn Đức tăng một số phật tử
in the club, with full karmic affinity,
trong câu lạc bộ đầy đủ nhân duyên về
participated in the program with the sincere and
tham gia chương trình với tâm trí thành
respectful hearts of the Buddhists. The Venerable Monks
tôn kính của quý phật tử Chư Tôn Đức đã
promised to accept the offerings, and
hứa Khả Thọ nhận sự cúng dường và giờ
now we invite you to focus your
này xin mời quý vị và các bạn cùng hướng
minds on the
tâm theo dõi chương
program: A bowl of rice from a thousand homes, a single person from ten thousand
trình một bát cơm ngàn nhà đơn thân vạn
miles
dặm
away, with a blue eye looking at the world, asking for directions, white clouds passing by, shaving the
xa mắt xanh nhìn Trần Thế hỏi đường mây
cow's head, oil falling down, wearing a cloak of
trắng qua cạo bò dầu xuống T
far-reaching decay, living a life of purity, the
khoác cả xa hoại sắc sống chế Ngự Thanh
Pure Body, Speech, and Mind, Peaceful and Tranquil Bowl, spreading
Cao Thân Khẩu Ý An
throughout every home, not
Tịnh bát Bình khắp mọi nhà chẳng tham
greedy, clinging to food, receiving all sentient beings
Luyến thức ăn nghiếp thụ các hữu tình
without discrimination, promising to eat
không phân biệt hẹn
well in the morning,
sáng khá thực
eliminating greed, bitterness, arrogance, and
trừ tham đắng ngã mạn cùng si
delusion, from secret, enthusiastically, equalizing all beings,
mê từ bí hăng bình
all creatures.
đẳng chúng sinh khắp muôn
A bowl of rice from a thousand homes, a single person from ten thousand
loài một bát cơm ngàn nhà đơn thân vạn
miles away, begging for
dặm xa khất thực bình bát
alms, benefiting all people and
Phước Lợi ích khắp nhân
heaven, leaving home to seek the holy path, the bowl of blessings in
thiên xất gia cầu thánh đạo bin bát
every home, eradicating false views, preaching the Dharma to save sentient beings.
Phước mọi nhà phá trừ các Tà kiến thuyết
[music]
[âm nhạc]
A bowl of rice from a thousand
một bát cơm ngàn
homes, a single person from ten thousand miles away, with a blue eye looking at
nhà đơn thân vạn dặm xa mắt xanh nhìn
the world, asking for directions, white clouds passing by, shaving the cow's head,
Trần Thế hỏi đường mây trắng qua cạo bò
oil falling down, wearing a cloak of
dầu xuống tốc
far-reaching decay, living a life of purity, the Pure Body, Speech, and Mind, Peaceful
khoác cả xa hoại sắc sống chê Ngự thành
and
cao Thân Khẩu Ý An
Tranquil Bowl, spreading throughout every home.  Without
Tịnh bát Bình khắp mọi nhà chẳng tham
attachment to food, one receives all sentient beings
Luyến thức ăn nhĩ hợp thụ các hữu tình
without discrimination, without craving, without attachment, without pride, without delusion, without
không phân biệt hẹn
selfishness, without desire, with
mê tư bí hăng bình
equality for all
đẳng chúng sinh khắp muôn
beings, one bowl of rice for a thousand homes, a single person
loài một bát cơm ngàn nhà đơn thân vạn
begging for alms for ten thousand miles,
dặm xa khất thực bình bát
merit and benefit for all beings, renouncing
Phước Lợi ích khắp nhân
worldly life to seek the holy path, merit and
thiên xuất gia cầu thánh đạo binh bát
benefit for all households, eliminating all evil, establishing the Dharma to save sentient beings.
Phước mọi nhà phá trừ các tạ yiên thiết
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Dear Buddhist followers and friends, the
sinh Kính thưa quý phật tử và các bạn
alms-giving and offering program commemorating the
chương trình đạt bát cúng dường kỷ niệm
2024 birthday of the Golden Cup Club
sinh nhật câu lạc bộ cốc vàng năm 2024
has concluded successfully. We hope that with the
đã kết thúc viên mãn mong rằng với sự
sincere offerings of the Buddhist followers to
chân thật cúng dường của các phật tử đến
the monastic community of Ba Vang Pagoda, all the
tăng đoàn chùa Ba Vàng mọi sở nguyện
good wishes of the Buddhist followers will be
thiện lành của các quý phật tử đều được
fulfilled. We wish the club to
thành tựu xin chúc cho câu lạc bộ sẽ
develop even more strongly to
ngày càng phát triển mạnh mẽ hơn nữa để
spread the Dharma throughout the world,
chuyển tải Phật pháp rộng khắp thế gian
bringing benefit and happiness to everyone.
đem lại lợi ích hạnh phúc cho mọi người
Thank you for following the
xin cảm ơn quý vị đã hướng tâm theo dõi
program. We wish you always be
chương trình Xin kính chúc quý vị luôn
protected under the light of the
được trở che Dưới Ánh Sáng Từ Quang của
Buddhas of the Ten Directions so that your body and mind may be at peace and you may
10 Phương Chư Phật để thân tâm an lạc tu
practice diligently. And now, goodbye and see you
tập tinh tấn Còn bây giờ Xin chào và hẹn
again.
lại